Guide to the Bronislaw Malinowski Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings of Others, 1910-1939; Series III
  - Freud, Sigmund. Drei Abhandlungen zur Sexualtheorie, annotated throughout by Malinowski, 1922 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - E. N. F. Review of The Sexual Life of Savages in North-Western Melanesia, by Bronislaw Malinowski, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Haddon, A. C. Review of The Children of the Sun by W. J. Perry, The Nation and the Athenaeum, 1923 September 29 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Lehmann, F. R. Review of The Sorcerers of Dobu, by R. F. Fortune [with an introduction by Malinowski], Geographischer Literatur, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Miller, Gerrit S., Jr. "Some Elements of Sexual Behavior in Primates and Their Possible Influence on the Beginnings of Human Social Development," reprinted from the Journal of Mammology, with notes and annotations by Malinowski, 1928 November (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Myers, Charles S. "A lecture on Freudian Psychology," reprinted from The Lancet, annotated by Malinowski, 1926 June (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Richards A. I. "Anthropological Problems in North-Eastern Rhodesia," reprinted from Africa, Vol. V. No. 2, 1932 April (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Richards A. I. Reviews of her book, Hunger and Work in a Savage Tribe; by Malcolm Burr in theLondon Sunday and unsigned review in the Times Literary Supplement [with penciled comments by Miss Richards], 1932 June 10, 23 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Seligman, C. G. The Melanesians of British New Guinea, annotated by Malinowski, 1910 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - E. S. Review of Argonauts of the Western Pacific, by Bronislaw Malinowski; carbon copy with corrections, incomplete, undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Descriptions of the notebooks of Sir J. G. Frazer and suggestion that they be published, author unknown, undated (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - "Social Relations of Science;" galley proof of an article to appear in Nature, author unknown, undated (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Articles and Reprints, 1926-1936 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Reprints, with inscriptions by the authors, 1928-1938 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Reprints, with inscriptions by the authors, 1938, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Proofs [fragments] (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - List of additional books, reprints, and pamphlets found among Malinowski's papers [now in a Paige box at the end of the collection], 1914-1939, undated (Box 31, Folder 29)
- Special Files, 1902-1946; Series IV
  Series IV contains one archive box of certificates, passports, bulletins, clippings, advertisements for Malinowski's books and lectures, and memorial tributes, and one archive box of family photographs.
  The arrangement of the first box is chronological. The photographs are, for the most part, undated and unidentified.
  - "Index lectionem," student record at the University of Cracow, 1902-1907 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Certificates attesting to Malinowski's good moral character, 1909 June 23, 1925 December 9 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Accounting books [with some personal notations], income tax statement, and receipt of Józefa Malinowska, mother of Bronislaw Malinowski, 1911-1917, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Passports [4], 1911-1929 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Official travel permits and certificates issued to an alien in wartime form the Commonwealth of Australia and the Territory of Papua, 1914-1918 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Travel brochures and souvenirs, 1914, 1935, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Advertisements, bulletins, and reports, miscellaneous, 1916-1937, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Contracts of service [B. Malinowski, employer], 1917, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Public notices of the death of Józefa Malinowska [mother of Bronislaw Malinowski], 1918 January 24 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Certificate of appointment as Local Correspondent for Papua of the Royal Anthropological Institute, 1919 October 14 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Advertisements for lectures by Malinowski, 1925-1938, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Advertisements for published works of Malinowski, 1928-1930, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1914, 1932-1938, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Bulletins of the Tercentenary of Harvard College, at which Malinowski received and honorary Doctor of Science degree, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Selected commentary on the paintings of Valetta Swann [second wife of Bronislaw Malinowski], 1938-1946 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - "Professor Bronislaw Malinowski, An Account of the Memorial Meeting held at the Royal Institution in London on July 13, 1942", 1943 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - "Commemoration of Professor Malinowski," reprinted from the Quarterly Bulletin of the Polish Institute of the Arts and Sciences in America, 1943 January (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Drawings and sketches, undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Family Photographs, undated (Box 33, Folder 20 - 28)
  - Postcards [no message], undated (Box 33, Folder 29)
- Additional Material, Accession 2004-M-022
  The accession consists of fieldwork materials of Malinowski and Lew Wallace, who were researching in from Mexico in 1940 and 1941. The accession contains field notes and notebooks, pamphlets, clippings, printed materials, charts, maps, and a manuscript, "The Economics of a Mexican Market System."
  The materials are arranged according to an organizational scheme established initially by Valetta Swan, who divided a majority of the field notes (Boxes 3-6) into fourteen "books." The materials also include an index, subsequently created by Ronald Waterbury.
  - Original field notebooks
    - Malinowski, Bronislaw
      - 1940 [3 volumes] (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
      - 1941 summer [3 volumes] (Box 1, Folder 4 - 6)
    - Wallace, Lew, 1941 June 29-August 24 (Box 2, Folder 7 - 11)
  - Pamphlets about Oaxaca, Circa 1926-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12 - 13)
  - Field notes
    - "Field notes of B. M. transcribed from Book II by Howard Reed", 1941 summer (Box 2, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Transcription of Malinowski dictation, appendix C, 1941 winter or 1942 spring (Box 2, Folder 16 - 17)
    - Index to the index and master index of Books 1-14, undated
    - Book 1
      - "Method and Theory," pp. 1-261, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - "Comments on 1941 MS by JDLF [J. de la Fuente] and VM [Valetta Malinowski]," pp. 262-311, 1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Book 2
      - "Summer, 1940 Transcriptions by JDLF," pp. 312-469, 1940, undated
      - "Summer 1941 VM Notes Book I," pp. 470-491, 1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Book 3: Transcriptions by JDLF., pp. 492-727, 1940 summer
    - Book 4
      - "BM Notes 1941," pp. 728-1046 (Box 4, Folder 31 - 34)
      - "Summer 1942 VM Notes Book II," pp. 1047-1081, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Book 5: Wallace, Lew notes
      - "Index, Critic of 1941 MS Letters, & Miscellaneous," pp. 1082-1170 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Books I and II, pp. 1171-1247, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Books III, IV, and V, pp. 1248-1302, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - "Survey of Santa Maria Atzompa," pp. 1303-1408, 1941 July-August (Box 4, Folder 39 - 40)
    - Book 6
      - "La Plaza Principal de Oaxaca," pp. 1409-1448, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Wallace, Lew: "First Descriptive Market Notes," pp. 1449-1470, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - "Oaxaca-Plaza Secundarias,"pp. 1471-1482, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - "Tlacolula-Tlacochehuaya-Guelavia-Guelase, Abasole," pp. 1483-1562, undated (Box 4, Folder 44 - 45)
    - Book 7
      - Ocotlan, pp. 1563-1643, undated (Box 5, Folder 46 - 47)
      - Ejutla and Etla, pp. 1644-1689, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Book 8
      - Zimatlan, Zaachila, Miahuatlan, San Pedro Apostal [with others], pp. 1690-1741, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - Huitzo and Telistlahuaca, S. Lorenzo Cacaotepec, "Plazas, General," Impuestos, pp. 1742-1789, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Salubridad, "Fiestas-Todo Santos, La Soledad," "Fiesta at San Miguel Minas," pp. 1790-1839, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Book 9
      - "Barter," "Viajes a Tehuantepec," "La Sierra," "Totolapan," Lew Wallace's trip to Peras, "Community Organization and Safety," pp. 1840-1905, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Consumption budgets, property, land tenure, pp. 1906-1978, undated
    - Book 10
      - Maize cultivation, pp. 1979-2044, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - "Venta de Maiz," pp. 2045-2202, undated (Box 5, Folder 54 - 55)
    - Book 11
      - "Mayordorias, Danza de la Pluma," pp. 2203-2306, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - "Casamientos," "Creencias y enfermedades," pp. 2307-2374, 1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Book 12
      - "Yunta in the field and in the meat market," "Butchering," pp. 2375-2508, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - Vegetable production; Alfalfa, frijol, and caña production; Chile; "Production of mezeal, leña, carbon," pp. 2510-2576, 1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Book 13
      - "Atzompa-Pottery production and sale," pp. 2577-2657, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - Atzompa-Pottery production and sale, "Loza: Oaxaca, Ocotlán, Coyotepec" [production], pp. 2658-2723, 1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Book 14
      - Metates; Ixtle: proudction and trade; Petates, sombreros, chiquihuites, huaraches, pp. 2724-2776, 1940-1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Merceria, menteles, rebozos; Yerbas and medicinas; Ropa hecha, pp. 2777-2817, undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Writings: "The Economics of a Mexican Market System," index and pp. 1-200, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 64 - 66)
  - Clippings and other printed material, with index, 1939-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Charts, maps, drawings, etc., with index, 1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Charts and maps, undated (Box 7)